{
    "id": "7180329115ed420cae4c14d5e7d41623",
    "title": "Conjunctions Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "No sooner had the ship touched shore ………………… a soldier of the tenth legion leaped into the water.",
            "description": "Sooner is a comparative word. We use ‘than’ after it.",
            "answers": [
                "than",
                "when",
                "before"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The boy went to school ……………… he had finished his meal.",
            "description": "We use 'as soon as' to suggest that something happens immediately after another. ",
            "answers": [
                "as long as",
                "as soon as",
                "as soon"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "……………….. ignorance is bliss, it is folly to be wise.",
            "description": "Where is a place word. It is also a relative adverb that can connect two clauses. ",
            "answers": [
                "Where",
                "There",
                "What"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "There was one philosopher ……………… chose to live in a tub.",
            "description": "Only 'who' can be used to refer to people. Whom can refer to people but it acts as the object of the verb in the relative clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "whom",
                "which"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He must have done his duty …………….. he is a conscientious man.",
            "description": "For is a coordinating conjunction. It can mean because. ",
            "answers": [
                "for",
                "so",
                "therefore"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He trudged on ……………….. he was very tired.",
            "description": "As and because have similar meanings. We use 'though' to connect two contrasting ideas.",
            "answers": [
                "because",
                "though",
                "even if",
                "as"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Your arguments are weighty ………………. they do not convince me.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "yet",
                "still",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "We must eat to live, ……………… we should not live to eat.",
            "description": "We use 'but' to connect contrasting ideas. ",
            "answers": [
                "and",
                "but",
                "or"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "They serve God well ……………… serve his children.",
            "description": "Who refers to people and act as the subject of the verb in the relative clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "what",
                "whom"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Control your passions ……………. they will control you.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "and",
                "or",
                "for"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He came oftener ……………… we expected.",
            "description": "After comparative expressions we use 'than', not 'when'.",
            "answers": [
                "than",
                "then",
                "when"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "My heart leaps up …………….. I behold a rainbow in the sky.",
            "description": "When and whenever are possible here. Whenever is more emphatic. ",
            "answers": [
                "when",
                "whenever",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        }
    ]
}